PRACHI VAVHAL

Location: Nashik,India. Contact Number: +91 9623732027 Email: prachisvavhal@gmail.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/prachisv04 **Website**: prachisv04.github.io

PROFILE SUMMARY

• Aspiring Software engineer with one year and seven months of experience, skilled in backend development using OOPs, Java, SQL, Spring Boot and related technologies.

 My pursuit centres on leading a healthy life, attaining continuous professional advancement, enhancing knowledge base, connecting people and developing new technologies as part of progressive organisation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Health Break February 2023–Present

- Determined to prioritise my well-being, following the accident I took a career hiatus to focus on my health.
- Utilised the time to stay progressive through continuous learning and assisting students with their academics and projects.

Associate Software Developer | Amdocs, Pune August 2021-February 2023

- Contributed to two clients as a crucial member of the scrum team, and collaborated with other teams in a cross-functional setting.
- Engaged in every development phase like analysis, implementation, testing, code review, and release.
- Executed over 20 user stories, contributing to 10%–50% of development in various sprint iterations.
- Enhanced the project code standard through resolution of more than 400 sonar issues.
- Addressed over 15 defects, leading to a 15% reduction in the project's pending issues.
- Proposed solutions and Actively engaged in discussions, resulting in a 60% increase in the personal participation rate.
- Skills: Java, J2EE, JDBC, Spring Boot, RDBMS, SQL, PLSQL, Object-Relational Mapping, Web Services, Perforce, JIRA, Microservices, Unit Testing, Debugging.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java: Object oriented Programming, J2EE, JDBC, Web Services, JSP, Collection API

Databases: SQL, PLSQL, (MySQL, Oracle, MS SQLServer)

Data Structures & algorithms, Design Patterns

Spring Framework, Microservices, Hibernate, SOAP, REST API

Web development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React.js

Tools: Maven, GIT, Perforce, Jira, Tomcat, Jenkins, Agile (SCRUM), XML, JSON, Postman.

Unit Testing, Cloud: GCP.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Sentiment Analyzer | December 2020-March 2021 | GitHub

Sentiment analysis module built using **Python** libraries, ReactJS, and MongoDB, based on machine learning techniques.

- Enforced rigorous data cleaning processes and categorization to 10K+ tweets extracted directly from social media.
- Presented sentiment trends using insightful graphs and maps (10 per category).

Project Management System | February 2020–April 2020 | GitHub

A web application built using Java, JSP, JDBC, and MYSQL, for students and facilitated scheduling and evaluation, resulting in automation of process by 80%.

 Designed and built Data Access layer, and Controller layer through reusable and maintainable code, affecting 40% of development of the system.

EDUCATION

BE (Bachelor of Engineering) in Information Technology | Pune

Pune Institute of Computer Technology, Pune. (8.38) August 2018–April 2021

Diploma in Computer Technology | Nashik

Government Polytechnic Nashik, Nashik. (89.31%) July 2015–May 2018

VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES

"Addiction": College Annual Event | January 2020

Headed the audition team, entitled to conduct auditions of over 200 students by proper communication and time management for all stakeholders.

• "Enthusia": College Technical Event: Coding Event Lead | September 2019

I guided a competitive coding event, where I managed over 100 enrolled participants. Incorporated multitasking capabilities by being part of various units at once.

LANGUAGES

Proficient in English, Hindi, and Marathi.